<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>minimalism on </title>
    <link>https://gaston.life/tags/minimalism/</link>
    <description>Recent content in minimalism on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://gaston.life/tags/minimalism/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Declutter Your Mind</title>
      <link>https://gaston.life/books/declutter-your-mind/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaston.life/books/declutter-your-mind/</guid>
      <description>Examine what you&amp;rsquo;re thinking and how it impacts your mood, stress levels, and well-being in general.
Thoughts are necessary for analytic thinking but if left unchecked your mind will roam like a monkey generating mental clutter, distracting you from the present moment.
Don&amp;rsquo;t quiet your mind with unhealthy behaviors like overeating, too much alcohol, excessive work, etc.
Identify what increases your daily stress. It can be information overload, physical clutter, or endless choices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ultralight</title>
      <link>https://gaston.life/books/ultralight/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaston.life/books/ultralight/</guid>
      <description>Travel on your terms, finding the freedom to enjoy your trips without carrying a huge burden on your back.
 The result is that our bags got lighter and lighter until they were no longer burdens, but things we barely noticed. — Leo Babauta
 Packing Light Looking Functionally Good Pick more practical clothes rather than trying to look spectacular. People won&amp;rsquo;t notice how you look, even if you look ready for a black-tie event.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simpler</title>
      <link>https://gaston.life/books/simpler/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaston.life/books/simpler/</guid>
      <description>Don&amp;rsquo;t hide behind being “busy”. Don&amp;rsquo;t fill your life with activities. Don&amp;rsquo;t spend time doing things regardless of their impact in your life.
Don&amp;rsquo;t think that just by going faster you&amp;rsquo;ll achieve more. It&amp;rsquo;s a fallacy. You won&amp;rsquo;t feel fulfilled even if you finish a thousand of unimportant tasks.
Don&amp;rsquo;t just count the activities you do, also weigh the importance of them.
Stop doing things that doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter thinking that you&amp;rsquo;ll have time for yourself later.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simplify</title>
      <link>https://gaston.life/books/simplify/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaston.life/books/simplify/</guid>
      <description>Minimalism is the intentional promotion of the things we most value and the removal of anything that distracts us from it. — Joshua Becker
 Declutter Look at your stuff. Is there anything out of place or disorganized? Anything you don&amp;rsquo;t need or love? Anything overflowing from a small place? That&amp;rsquo;s clutter.
Discover the hidden costs of clutter. Space, even in your home, costs money. You have to clean and organize your clutter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Power of No</title>
      <link>https://gaston.life/books/the-power-of-no/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaston.life/books/the-power-of-no/</guid>
      <description>Fear Ask for help even if you feel that you are overexposing yourself, as it&amp;rsquo;s the most courageous thing you can do.
We are taught to please more than to take chances. Take chances and live a fearless life.
Dial down jealousy by realising that your life is abundant. Jealousy is just the fear of losing something.
We are no longer living in scarcity. Look for the abundance in your life, even when you feel desperate, hurt, or defeated.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
