<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>other on </title>
    <link>https://gaston.life/tags/other/</link>
    <description>Recent content in other on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://gaston.life/tags/other/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Sure You&#39;re Joking, Mr Feynman!</title>
      <link>https://gaston.life/books/surely-youre-joking-mr-feynman/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaston.life/books/surely-youre-joking-mr-feynman/</guid>
      <description>These notes are not a summary of his stories but the lessons that I was able to extract from his stories. His stories are much, much better. understand Feynman a little bit better then definitely read his book._
 The first principle is that you must not fool yourself—and you are the easiest person to fool. — Richard Feynman
 There is always resistance to innovation, to doing things differently. The people that are before you are the smart ones, the ones that made it to where they are and they are not always open to new ideas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Love Yourself Like Your Life Depends On It</title>
      <link>https://gaston.life/books/love-yourself/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaston.life/books/love-yourself/</guid>
      <description>Repeat to yourself &amp;ldquo;I love myself&amp;rdquo; all the time until it becomes the anchor, the one true thing.
Don&amp;rsquo;t give things more importance than what they deserve. Don&amp;rsquo;t care about anything else. Just love yourself. Life loves you back when you love yourself.
 Your job is purely to love yourself. Truly and deeply. Feel it. Again and again. — Kamal Ravikant
 Most of the time you think you&amp;rsquo;re thinking but you&amp;rsquo;re actually remembering.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Total Money Makeover</title>
      <link>https://gaston.life/books/the-total-money-makeover/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaston.life/books/the-total-money-makeover/</guid>
      <description>All your money problems starts with you. The first step is confronting yourself. Consider how you handle relationships, emotional situations, and your spirituality.
Focus on improving your money habits. Great personal finances is 80% behavior and 20% knowledge.
Prefer setting up automatic measures to help you cultivate good money habits and to get rid of the bad ones.
Continuously practice delayed gratification in favor of greater results. Stop wanting to be “normal”.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
