<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hi, I&#39;m Gastón Jorquera on </title>
    <link>https://gaston.life/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hi, I&#39;m Gastón Jorquera on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://gaston.life/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Hugo: From Zero to One</title>
      <link>https://gaston.life/writings/hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaston.life/writings/hugo/</guid>
      <description>What is Hugo? Hugo is a CLI tool to build and maintain static HTML sites from source code. With Hugo you define the structure and style of the site once so that you can focus on the content. After you have an initial structure, style, and content, Hugo will be able to automatically include partials and layouts into pages, generate sitemaps, and build lists based completely on the content you write.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Site Style</title>
      <link>https://gaston.life/writings/site-style/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaston.life/writings/site-style/</guid>
      <description>Headings The following HTML &amp;lt;h1&amp;gt;—&amp;lt;h6&amp;gt; elements represent six levels of section headings. &amp;lt;h1&amp;gt; is the highest section level while &amp;lt;h6&amp;gt; is the lowest.
H1 H2 H3 H4 H5 H6 Paragraph Xerum, quo qui aut unt expliquam qui dolut labo. Aque venitatiusda cum, voluptionse latur sitiae dolessi aut parist aut dollo enim qui voluptate ma dolestendit peritin re plis aut quas inctum laceat est volestemque commosa as cus endigna tectur, offic to cor sequas etum rerum idem sintibus eiur?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Declutter Your Mind</title>
      <link>https://gaston.life/books/declutter-your-mind/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaston.life/books/declutter-your-mind/</guid>
      <description>Examine what you&amp;rsquo;re thinking and how it impacts your mood, stress levels, and well-being in general.
Thoughts are necessary for analytic thinking but if left unchecked your mind will roam like a monkey generating mental clutter, distracting you from the present moment.
Don&amp;rsquo;t quiet your mind with unhealthy behaviors like overeating, too much alcohol, excessive work, etc.
Identify what increases your daily stress. It can be information overload, physical clutter, or endless choices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Flinch</title>
      <link>https://gaston.life/books/the-flinch/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaston.life/books/the-flinch/</guid>
      <description>In a fight, there is a fundamental difference between boxers and everyone else. The guys who have trained are different. If you hit them, they don&amp;rsquo;t flinch. — Julien Smith
 In this age, getting the information is not the problem. The flinch is your real problem. And more information won&amp;rsquo;t help you.
What is the flinch?
Anything that supports the status quo. The initial rejection whenever you want to do something.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Convict Conditioning</title>
      <link>https://gaston.life/books/convict-conditioning/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaston.life/books/convict-conditioning/</guid>
      <description>Note: These notes doesn&amp;rsquo;t include the actual calisthenics program explained in the book.
 Calisthenics (&amp;hellip;) it comes from the ancient Greek kallos meaning &amp;ldquo;beauty&amp;rdquo;, and sthénos, which means &amp;ldquo;strength&amp;rdquo;. — Paul Wade
 Calisthenics is a strength training system.
These are the main benefits of doing calisthenics:
 It requires very little equipment because they are exercises using your own bodyweight. It&amp;rsquo;s also free. It develops functional athletic abilities because you learn to work and move your body.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sure You&#39;re Joking, Mr Feynman!</title>
      <link>https://gaston.life/books/surely-youre-joking-mr-feynman/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaston.life/books/surely-youre-joking-mr-feynman/</guid>
      <description>These notes are not a summary of his stories but the lessons that I was able to extract from his stories. His stories are much, much better. understand Feynman a little bit better then definitely read his book._
 The first principle is that you must not fool yourself—and you are the easiest person to fool. — Richard Feynman
 There is always resistance to innovation, to doing things differently. The people that are before you are the smart ones, the ones that made it to where they are and they are not always open to new ideas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Burn the Fat, Feed the Muscle</title>
      <link>https://gaston.life/books/burn-the-fat-feed-the-muscle/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaston.life/books/burn-the-fat-feed-the-muscle/</guid>
      <description>To improve your body (getting leaner and healthier) you need to work on different areas. Achieving a very lean body is the result of a lifestyle change.
There areas you need to work on are the following:
 Mental training Nutrition Weight training Cardio training  To obtain permanent results you need to adopt new, healthier habits that you can maintain for the rest of your life. These habits include the way you think, the way you eat, and the way you move.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Food Rules, An Eater&#39;s Manual</title>
      <link>https://gaston.life/books/food-rules/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaston.life/books/food-rules/</guid>
      <description>I learned that in fact science knows a lot less about nutrition than you would expect—that in fact nutrition science is, to put it charitably, a very young science. — Michael Pollan
 Two facts about nutrition and diet:
 Western diet (lots of processed food, added sugar and fat, refined grains) correlates with obesity, type 2 diabetes, cardiovascular disease, and cancer. Other diets generally don&amp;rsquo;t suffer from these chronic diseases.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sleep Smarter</title>
      <link>https://gaston.life/books/sleep-smarter/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaston.life/books/sleep-smarter/</guid>
      <description>Being awake breaks your body and sleep is the way to fix it and make it stronger.
You need sleep to have the body and health you want. You can&amp;rsquo;t be the best version of yourself if you&amp;rsquo;re tired.
See sleep as an incredible indulgence, as something you&amp;rsquo;re really looking forward to.
General Advice Avoid using sunglasses, they inhibit the natural exposure to light you need.
Learn to use coffee. Coffee has a 6 hours half-life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ultralight</title>
      <link>https://gaston.life/books/ultralight/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaston.life/books/ultralight/</guid>
      <description>Travel on your terms, finding the freedom to enjoy your trips without carrying a huge burden on your back.
 The result is that our bags got lighter and lighter until they were no longer burdens, but things we barely noticed. — Leo Babauta
 Packing Light Looking Functionally Good Pick more practical clothes rather than trying to look spectacular. People won&amp;rsquo;t notice how you look, even if you look ready for a black-tie event.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Love Yourself Like Your Life Depends On It</title>
      <link>https://gaston.life/books/love-yourself/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaston.life/books/love-yourself/</guid>
      <description>Repeat to yourself &amp;ldquo;I love myself&amp;rdquo; all the time until it becomes the anchor, the one true thing.
Don&amp;rsquo;t give things more importance than what they deserve. Don&amp;rsquo;t care about anything else. Just love yourself. Life loves you back when you love yourself.
 Your job is purely to love yourself. Truly and deeply. Feel it. Again and again. — Kamal Ravikant
 Most of the time you think you&amp;rsquo;re thinking but you&amp;rsquo;re actually remembering.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Master Todoist</title>
      <link>https://gaston.life/books/master-todoist/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaston.life/books/master-todoist/</guid>
      <description>You can&amp;rsquo;t store all your ideas, tasks, and appointments in your mind. Life is just too complicated.
Develop the habit of capturing everything that comes to your mind in one place and the habit of periodically reviewing them. Only by doing so, you&amp;rsquo;ll be able let go and fully concentrate on the task at hand.
 It has been said that once upon a time, the word priority was used in the singular form, which meant you could only have one priority at a time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Stop Worrying and Start Living</title>
      <link>https://gaston.life/books/how-to-stop-worrying-and-start-living/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaston.life/books/how-to-stop-worrying-and-start-living/</guid>
      <description>Your business is not to see what lies dimly at a distance but to do what lies clearly at hand.
Live every day compartmentalized. Shut out the dead yesterdays and the unborn tomorrows.
 The load of tomorrow, added to that of yesterday, carried today, makes the strongest falter. — Dale Carnegie
 The best way to prepare for tomorrow is to concentrate and do your absolute best today.
Plan for tomorrow but have no anxiety for it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Daily Stoic</title>
      <link>https://gaston.life/books/the-daily-stoic/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaston.life/books/the-daily-stoic/</guid>
      <description>Build the daily habit of morning preparation and evening reflection. Surrender and trust, through sleep, that tomorrow you can start all over again.
Three disciplines:
 Perception: How we see and filter the world around us. Action: Decisions and what we do and to what end. Will: How we deal with things we cannot change and figure out our place in the world.   Virtue—made up as it is of justice, honesty, discipline, and courage—is the only thing worth striving for.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clean Coder</title>
      <link>https://gaston.life/books/clean-coder/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaston.life/books/clean-coder/</guid>
      <description>Professionalism is all about taking responsibility. — Robert Martin
 Don&amp;rsquo;t take pride or honor in something that you won&amp;rsquo;t be held accountable for.
 Software is too complex to create without bugs. Unfortunately that doesn&amp;rsquo;t let you off the hook. The human body is too complex to understand in it&amp;rsquo;s entirety, but doctors still take an oath to do no harm. — Robert Martin
 You will create bugs, you will make errors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ego is the Enemy</title>
      <link>https://gaston.life/books/ego-is-the-enemy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaston.life/books/ego-is-the-enemy/</guid>
      <description>We might not ever be straight, but we can strive to be straighter — Ryan Holiday
 Your worst enemy is your own ego: the need to be more than, better than, recognized for, etc. It&amp;rsquo;s the sense of superiority that exceeds the bounds of your confidence and ability.
Ego prevents you from realizing that you&amp;rsquo;re just not that good. It prevents having a honest connection with the world around you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Subtle Art of Not Giving a F*ck</title>
      <link>https://gaston.life/books/the-subtle-art-of-not-giving-a-fck/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaston.life/books/the-subtle-art-of-not-giving-a-fck/</guid>
      <description>Stop giving a fuck about more. Stop letting others, or life, dictate what you should give a fuck about.
Don&amp;rsquo;t follow the conventional life advice of being positive and happy. This focuses on what you lack, on what you should have been but failed to be. Pursuing something only makes you very aware of the fact that you don&amp;rsquo;t have it.
Accept that having negative experiences and feelings — anxiety, fear, guilt — is completely normal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tribes</title>
      <link>https://gaston.life/books/tribes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaston.life/books/tribes/</guid>
      <description>People want to be a part of something bigger, but showing up isn&amp;rsquo;t enough.
A tribe is a group of people with a shared interest and a way to communicate, and they needs leaders.
If you want to be a leader, don&amp;rsquo;t be boring. Do a great job instead.
 &amp;ldquo;Good enough&amp;rdquo; stopped being good enough a long time ago. So why not be great? — Seth Godin
 Don&amp;rsquo;t try to be a leader just because you can or for selfish reasons; wait for your right cause.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meditations</title>
      <link>https://gaston.life/books/meditations/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaston.life/books/meditations/</guid>
      <description>Realize that character needs training and discipline.
Don&amp;rsquo;t waste time on nonsense, don&amp;rsquo;t give the small things more time than they deserve.
Accept that the world is maintained by change. Nothing can exist without change; you can&amp;rsquo;t even eat without you changing your food.
Don&amp;rsquo;t live your life as you have endless years ahead of you. While you&amp;rsquo;re alive, be and do good. Think that you&amp;rsquo;re dead; now enjoy what&amp;rsquo;s left of your life and live it properly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effective Java</title>
      <link>https://gaston.life/books/effective-java/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaston.life/books/effective-java/</guid>
      <description>Clarity and simplicity are of paramount importance. The user of a module should never be surprised by its behavior. Modules should be as small as possible but no smaller. Code should be reused rather than copied. The dependencies between modules should be kept to a minimum. — Joshua Bloch
 Creating and Destroying Objects Consider static factory methods (not Factory Method pattern) for object instantiation. You can cache instances to control the number of instances, and return nonpublic subtypes exposing one public API hiding the different implementations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time Well Spent</title>
      <link>https://gaston.life/books/time-well-spent/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaston.life/books/time-well-spent/</guid>
      <description>Time management is not about managing time. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter if you have the perfect tools or if you were able to cram up every waking minute of your day with tasks.
If you&amp;rsquo;re doing too many thing you&amp;rsquo;ll end up exhausted without enjoying life.
If you&amp;rsquo;re doing the wrong things you&amp;rsquo;ll end up where you never wanted to be.
If you&amp;rsquo;re not doing anything you&amp;rsquo;ll end up hating that “freedom” and reacting to whatever happens around you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Way of the Superior Man</title>
      <link>https://gaston.life/books/the-way-of-the-superior-man/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaston.life/books/the-way-of-the-superior-man/</guid>
      <description>Stop waiting for the good stuff to come, look for it yourself. Spend at least 1 hour a day doing whatever you&amp;rsquo;re currently waiting to do.
Listen to others and then make a decision based on your new perspective. It&amp;rsquo;s your responsibility to make your own decision. Never betray yourself and your values to please anyone.
Don&amp;rsquo;t seek fulfillment, neither through work nor women, you&amp;rsquo;re already full.
Your Edge  A superior man is free in feeling and action, even amidst great pain and hurt.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effective Programming</title>
      <link>https://gaston.life/books/effective-programming/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaston.life/books/effective-programming/</guid>
      <description>Being a Programmer Don&amp;rsquo;t become a programmer only because someone tells you to. Become a programmer because you want to solve problems, you want to write your own rules, and you enjoy doing it.
The most important skill for a programmer is the ability to effectively communicate ideas. This leads to code that communicates intention. The only work that&amp;rsquo;s reusable is the one that you understand what it communicates.
Always keep on studying and practicing on how to write.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Don&#39;t Make Me Think</title>
      <link>https://gaston.life/books/dont-make-me-think/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaston.life/books/dont-make-me-think/</guid>
      <description>Before you start building your web site, have some users try your competitors web sites and take notes on the problems they have. Consider this pain points when designing and building your own web site.
Don&amp;rsquo;t make your users think. Strive to make web pages self-evident or, at the very least, self-explanatory. Every time a user stops to consider if they&amp;rsquo;re on the right path, it adds to their cognitive workload and distracts them from their actual task.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Obstacle is the Way</title>
      <link>https://gaston.life/books/the-obstacle-is-the-way/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaston.life/books/the-obstacle-is-the-way/</guid>
      <description>Obstacles aren&amp;rsquo;t telling you to stop, they&amp;rsquo;re only letting you know that you need to find another way.
Realize that many of your problems come from inside, from having too much, from living in some of the most prosperous times in history.
 Great times are great softeners. — Ryan Holiday
 Expect and embrace obstacles, they will make you a better person.
The Discipline of Perception Learn to limit your passions and their control over your life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Total Money Makeover</title>
      <link>https://gaston.life/books/the-total-money-makeover/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaston.life/books/the-total-money-makeover/</guid>
      <description>All your money problems starts with you. The first step is confronting yourself. Consider how you handle relationships, emotional situations, and your spirituality.
Focus on improving your money habits. Great personal finances is 80% behavior and 20% knowledge.
Prefer setting up automatic measures to help you cultivate good money habits and to get rid of the bad ones.
Continuously practice delayed gratification in favor of greater results. Stop wanting to be “normal”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simpler</title>
      <link>https://gaston.life/books/simpler/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaston.life/books/simpler/</guid>
      <description>Don&amp;rsquo;t hide behind being “busy”. Don&amp;rsquo;t fill your life with activities. Don&amp;rsquo;t spend time doing things regardless of their impact in your life.
Don&amp;rsquo;t think that just by going faster you&amp;rsquo;ll achieve more. It&amp;rsquo;s a fallacy. You won&amp;rsquo;t feel fulfilled even if you finish a thousand of unimportant tasks.
Don&amp;rsquo;t just count the activities you do, also weigh the importance of them.
Stop doing things that doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter thinking that you&amp;rsquo;ll have time for yourself later.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Growing Object Oriented Software, Guided by Tests</title>
      <link>https://gaston.life/books/growing-object-oriented-software-guided-by-tests/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaston.life/books/growing-object-oriented-software-guided-by-tests/</guid>
      <description>Unless performance is a requirement, optimize for readability. Code is read far more than it&amp;rsquo;s written.
Team productivity is mostly improved by a readable codebase.
External quality measures the level on which the system meets its customers and users needs. Internal quality measures the level on which the system meets its developers and administrator needs.
When developing always consider the external quality trade-offs as well as internal quality trade-offs. Never forget about the internal quality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>To-Do List Makeover</title>
      <link>https://gaston.life/books/to-do-list-makeover/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaston.life/books/to-do-list-makeover/</guid>
      <description>The key to make this system work is to accept that:
 Knowing how to identify what&amp;rsquo;s important is crucial. These are usually tasks with impending deadlines or tasks that has great impact to your goals. There are different types of tasks. Small tasks with clear completion criteria are easier to complete and builds momentum. Creating tasks thinking on how to achieve the end result are better. Tasks are not life or death activities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Freedom Handbook</title>
      <link>https://gaston.life/books/the-freedom-handbook/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaston.life/books/the-freedom-handbook/</guid>
      <description>Your Freedom Depends on You Stop thinking on freedom as a restraint. There is nothing you have to break free from.
 Nothing outside ourselves will ever make us free. — Jeff Hirz
 Stop thinking you&amp;rsquo;re going to be happy once you achieve something, anything.
Remove everything that takes energy from you and doesn&amp;rsquo;t contribute towards your well being.
Decide to stop spending time cleaning things you don&amp;rsquo;t find beautiful.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tyranny of the Urgent</title>
      <link>https://gaston.life/books/tyranny-of-the-urgent/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaston.life/books/tyranny-of-the-urgent/</guid>
      <description>If you feel like your days are too short, more time each day is not the solution. Parkinson&amp;rsquo;s Law seems to be a thing.
Fear, doubt and anxiety over the past arises when we look at all our unfinished tasks.
Realise the fact that urgent tasks are taking time from important tasks.
This is a problem of priorities, not time. The problem is the choice you make.
It&amp;rsquo;s not your responsibility to do something just because you can, however urgent it is.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simplify</title>
      <link>https://gaston.life/books/simplify/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaston.life/books/simplify/</guid>
      <description>Minimalism is the intentional promotion of the things we most value and the removal of anything that distracts us from it. — Joshua Becker
 Declutter Look at your stuff. Is there anything out of place or disorganized? Anything you don&amp;rsquo;t need or love? Anything overflowing from a small place? That&amp;rsquo;s clutter.
Discover the hidden costs of clutter. Space, even in your home, costs money. You have to clean and organize your clutter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Power of No</title>
      <link>https://gaston.life/books/the-power-of-no/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaston.life/books/the-power-of-no/</guid>
      <description>Fear Ask for help even if you feel that you are overexposing yourself, as it&amp;rsquo;s the most courageous thing you can do.
We are taught to please more than to take chances. Take chances and live a fearless life.
Dial down jealousy by realising that your life is abundant. Jealousy is just the fear of losing something.
We are no longer living in scarcity. Look for the abundance in your life, even when you feel desperate, hurt, or defeated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some Thoughts About Relationships</title>
      <link>https://gaston.life/books/some-thoughts-about-relationships/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaston.life/books/some-thoughts-about-relationships/</guid>
      <description>All relationships are different. These guidelines should serve as ideas on which to build your own guidelines. Figure out what makes sense to you, and commit on a daily basis.
Develop the habit of questioning the pre-established notions about relationships. Never play a predetermined role.
Stress test your relationship by traveling together. The randomness and uncertainty of traveling brings up the best and worst of everyone.
Be Rational Believe in cause and effect, continuous improvement, and looking for solutions to problems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>As a Man Thinketh</title>
      <link>https://gaston.life/books/as-a-man-thinketh/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaston.life/books/as-a-man-thinketh/</guid>
      <description>Beware of your thoughts, as you are the sum of them. You are made or unmade by your thoughts. Whatever you achieve or fail is a result of them. Act is the result of thought.
You are in the exact place you need to be so you can learn and evolve.
Take care and cultivate your thoughts. Get rid of the wrong, useless and impure thoughts.
Find the purpose to your thoughts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Universe Doesn&#39;t Give a Flying Fuck About You</title>
      <link>https://gaston.life/books/the-universe-doesnt-give-a-flying-fuck-about-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaston.life/books/the-universe-doesnt-give-a-flying-fuck-about-you/</guid>
      <description>Looking up the sky gives me the existential chills, too. Do it at your own risk.
Don&amp;rsquo;t deny the fact that you are going to die. It&amp;rsquo;s as certain as the fact that you were born.
Don&amp;rsquo;t act as if what you do will stay forever in perpetuity.
Everything that you&amp;rsquo;ve experienced, will last for a brief moment. Then it&amp;rsquo;ll be gone, along with you.
Realize that you are here now, and then you won&amp;rsquo;t.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You Are Dying, and Your World is a Lie</title>
      <link>https://gaston.life/books/you-are-dying-and-your-world-is-a-lie/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaston.life/books/you-are-dying-and-your-world-is-a-lie/</guid>
      <description>Cave men were in danger. They could die from a cut that got infected, or a twisted ankle that slowed them. From bad water or food gone scarce. You, on the other hand, are not in danger anymore.
Your fears about your job, your finances, or your social status are not real. Those things will not kill you. Life will go on.
Imagine you are diagnosed with cancer and given six months to live.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Make it Stick</title>
      <link>https://gaston.life/books/make-it-stick/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaston.life/books/make-it-stick/</guid>
      <description>Learning: we mean acquiring knowledge and skills and having them readily available from memory so you can make sense of future problems and opportunities. — Peter Brown
 Learning is a skill. Develop it, as it&amp;rsquo;ll be your most valuable skill.
Learning is hard and it usually isn&amp;rsquo;t enjoyable. It depends more on the kind of effort spent while learning than on genetics. Be patient and determined.
In practice, there&amp;rsquo;s no limit to what we can remember.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lying</title>
      <link>https://gaston.life/books/lying/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaston.life/books/lying/</guid>
      <description>Lies  To lie is to intentionally mislead others when they expect honest communication. — Sam Harris
 Don&amp;rsquo;t lie, even if you think a white lie is better than being honest. You don&amp;rsquo;t know when it might turn itself around and generate more harm than good.
Don&amp;rsquo;t intentionally communicate something you don&amp;rsquo;t believe. Others might act on that falsehood, generating all kinds of problems that you may not be able to predict.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boredom is a Good Thing</title>
      <link>https://gaston.life/writings/boredom/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaston.life/writings/boredom/</guid>
      <description>Do you remember a decade or two ago when you were bored? Do you remember how it felt? Not knowing what to do? Bouncing out ideas with your friends (or imaginary friends)?
Did you stop to think about how I asked &amp;ldquo;a decade or two ago&amp;rdquo; and not &amp;ldquo;a week or two ago&amp;rdquo; or even &amp;ldquo;a year or two ago&amp;rdquo;?
When was the last time you were bored?
It&amp;rsquo;s hard to feel bored with the constant notifications and noise around us due to technology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Clean from Notifications</title>
      <link>https://gaston.life/writings/notifications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaston.life/writings/notifications/</guid>
      <description>I bought my first smartphone because I wanted to have my calendar accessible from my computer and phone. I kept forgetting my appointments and scheduling several things at the same time. Sounds reasonable, right?
Fast forward a couple of years and I found myself compulsively checking my phone. At first I was just trying to take advantage of idle moments while commuting or when waiting for something. By the end, I was checking my phone before even getting out of bed, while having dinner (and watching TV), while trying to work, even while having a good time with some friends.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning from Books</title>
      <link>https://gaston.life/writings/notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaston.life/writings/notes/</guid>
      <description>I bet you can recommend me several books that have changed your life in some way. But, can you honestly say that you have internalized the teachings of every one of them? Maybe you can&amp;rsquo;t, but can you at least summarize them? If not, can you even tell me the key topics?
Are you satisfied with what you remember from those essential and life changing books? If you&amp;rsquo;re not, then this might help you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effective Photo Management</title>
      <link>https://gaston.life/writings/photos/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaston.life/writings/photos/</guid>
      <description>What I like about photographs is that they capture a moment that&amp;rsquo;s gone forever, impossible to reproduce. — Karl Lagerfeld
 Taking photos helps us remember those moments that are gone forever; our time spent with friends and family, our trips abroad, our life. They help us remember places we&amp;rsquo;re not going to visit again, experiences we&amp;rsquo;re not going to live again, and those who we&amp;rsquo;ll never be able to talk to again.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resting into Productivity</title>
      <link>https://gaston.life/writings/resting/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaston.life/writings/resting/</guid>
      <description>We all like to learn and be good at what we do. Right?
But, have you ever found yourself trying to be productive by making the most of idle moments? Answering emails at waiting rooms, listening to audiobooks while driving, or reading books cover to cover to learn new things?
Are you convinced that to be more productive you have to work more hours and reducing your not working moments?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Todoist and Pomodoros</title>
      <link>https://gaston.life/writings/todoist/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaston.life/writings/todoist/</guid>
      <description>I will not explain what Todoist or The Pomodoro Technique are nor its benefits. There are already lots of articles and blog posts doing that. I will only say that if you haven&amp;rsquo;t used them, you should at least try them. (I understand that they might not work for you, but it might give you a hint on what might.) If you are already using them, then awesome!
On this article I will focus on how to use them together since Todoist doesn&amp;rsquo;t support The Pomodoro Technique out of the box.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Not Found</title>
      <link>https://gaston.life/404.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaston.life/404.html</guid>
      <description>The page you&amp;rsquo;re looking for does not exist.
 You have power over your mind - not outside events. Realize this, and you will find strength.
— Marcus Aurelius
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now</title>
      <link>https://gaston.life/now/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaston.life/now/</guid>
      <description>(This is a now page.)
After thinking for a long time, I realized that I was doing too many different things without a common theme. This meant that I couldn&amp;rsquo;t transfer knowledge nor skills from the different things I was trying out.
So, I decided that I will only focus on:
 Health: Build habits and routines to improve my sleep, meals, and exercises so that I can perform better at indoor climbing.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
