<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>stoicism on </title>
    <link>https://gaston.life/tags/stoicism/</link>
    <description>Recent content in stoicism on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://gaston.life/tags/stoicism/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Flinch</title>
      <link>https://gaston.life/books/the-flinch/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaston.life/books/the-flinch/</guid>
      <description>In a fight, there is a fundamental difference between boxers and everyone else. The guys who have trained are different. If you hit them, they don&amp;rsquo;t flinch. — Julien Smith
 In this age, getting the information is not the problem. The flinch is your real problem. And more information won&amp;rsquo;t help you.
What is the flinch?
Anything that supports the status quo. The initial rejection whenever you want to do something.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Stop Worrying and Start Living</title>
      <link>https://gaston.life/books/how-to-stop-worrying-and-start-living/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaston.life/books/how-to-stop-worrying-and-start-living/</guid>
      <description>Your business is not to see what lies dimly at a distance but to do what lies clearly at hand.
Live every day compartmentalized. Shut out the dead yesterdays and the unborn tomorrows.
 The load of tomorrow, added to that of yesterday, carried today, makes the strongest falter. — Dale Carnegie
 The best way to prepare for tomorrow is to concentrate and do your absolute best today.
Plan for tomorrow but have no anxiety for it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Daily Stoic</title>
      <link>https://gaston.life/books/the-daily-stoic/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaston.life/books/the-daily-stoic/</guid>
      <description>Build the daily habit of morning preparation and evening reflection. Surrender and trust, through sleep, that tomorrow you can start all over again.
Three disciplines:
 Perception: How we see and filter the world around us. Action: Decisions and what we do and to what end. Will: How we deal with things we cannot change and figure out our place in the world.   Virtue—made up as it is of justice, honesty, discipline, and courage—is the only thing worth striving for.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ego is the Enemy</title>
      <link>https://gaston.life/books/ego-is-the-enemy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaston.life/books/ego-is-the-enemy/</guid>
      <description>We might not ever be straight, but we can strive to be straighter — Ryan Holiday
 Your worst enemy is your own ego: the need to be more than, better than, recognized for, etc. It&amp;rsquo;s the sense of superiority that exceeds the bounds of your confidence and ability.
Ego prevents you from realizing that you&amp;rsquo;re just not that good. It prevents having a honest connection with the world around you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Subtle Art of Not Giving a F*ck</title>
      <link>https://gaston.life/books/the-subtle-art-of-not-giving-a-fck/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaston.life/books/the-subtle-art-of-not-giving-a-fck/</guid>
      <description>Stop giving a fuck about more. Stop letting others, or life, dictate what you should give a fuck about.
Don&amp;rsquo;t follow the conventional life advice of being positive and happy. This focuses on what you lack, on what you should have been but failed to be. Pursuing something only makes you very aware of the fact that you don&amp;rsquo;t have it.
Accept that having negative experiences and feelings — anxiety, fear, guilt — is completely normal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meditations</title>
      <link>https://gaston.life/books/meditations/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaston.life/books/meditations/</guid>
      <description>Realize that character needs training and discipline.
Don&amp;rsquo;t waste time on nonsense, don&amp;rsquo;t give the small things more time than they deserve.
Accept that the world is maintained by change. Nothing can exist without change; you can&amp;rsquo;t even eat without you changing your food.
Don&amp;rsquo;t live your life as you have endless years ahead of you. While you&amp;rsquo;re alive, be and do good. Think that you&amp;rsquo;re dead; now enjoy what&amp;rsquo;s left of your life and live it properly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Obstacle is the Way</title>
      <link>https://gaston.life/books/the-obstacle-is-the-way/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaston.life/books/the-obstacle-is-the-way/</guid>
      <description>Obstacles aren&amp;rsquo;t telling you to stop, they&amp;rsquo;re only letting you know that you need to find another way.
Realize that many of your problems come from inside, from having too much, from living in some of the most prosperous times in history.
 Great times are great softeners. — Ryan Holiday
 Expect and embrace obstacles, they will make you a better person.
The Discipline of Perception Learn to limit your passions and their control over your life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Freedom Handbook</title>
      <link>https://gaston.life/books/the-freedom-handbook/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaston.life/books/the-freedom-handbook/</guid>
      <description>Your Freedom Depends on You Stop thinking on freedom as a restraint. There is nothing you have to break free from.
 Nothing outside ourselves will ever make us free. — Jeff Hirz
 Stop thinking you&amp;rsquo;re going to be happy once you achieve something, anything.
Remove everything that takes energy from you and doesn&amp;rsquo;t contribute towards your well being.
Decide to stop spending time cleaning things you don&amp;rsquo;t find beautiful.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>As a Man Thinketh</title>
      <link>https://gaston.life/books/as-a-man-thinketh/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaston.life/books/as-a-man-thinketh/</guid>
      <description>Beware of your thoughts, as you are the sum of them. You are made or unmade by your thoughts. Whatever you achieve or fail is a result of them. Act is the result of thought.
You are in the exact place you need to be so you can learn and evolve.
Take care and cultivate your thoughts. Get rid of the wrong, useless and impure thoughts.
Find the purpose to your thoughts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Universe Doesn&#39;t Give a Flying Fuck About You</title>
      <link>https://gaston.life/books/the-universe-doesnt-give-a-flying-fuck-about-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaston.life/books/the-universe-doesnt-give-a-flying-fuck-about-you/</guid>
      <description>Looking up the sky gives me the existential chills, too. Do it at your own risk.
Don&amp;rsquo;t deny the fact that you are going to die. It&amp;rsquo;s as certain as the fact that you were born.
Don&amp;rsquo;t act as if what you do will stay forever in perpetuity.
Everything that you&amp;rsquo;ve experienced, will last for a brief moment. Then it&amp;rsquo;ll be gone, along with you.
Realize that you are here now, and then you won&amp;rsquo;t.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You Are Dying, and Your World is a Lie</title>
      <link>https://gaston.life/books/you-are-dying-and-your-world-is-a-lie/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaston.life/books/you-are-dying-and-your-world-is-a-lie/</guid>
      <description>Cave men were in danger. They could die from a cut that got infected, or a twisted ankle that slowed them. From bad water or food gone scarce. You, on the other hand, are not in danger anymore.
Your fears about your job, your finances, or your social status are not real. Those things will not kill you. Life will go on.
Imagine you are diagnosed with cancer and given six months to live.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
