<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>relationships on </title>
    <link>https://gaston.life/tags/relationships/</link>
    <description>Recent content in relationships on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://gaston.life/tags/relationships/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Tribes</title>
      <link>https://gaston.life/books/tribes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaston.life/books/tribes/</guid>
      <description>People want to be a part of something bigger, but showing up isn&amp;rsquo;t enough.
A tribe is a group of people with a shared interest and a way to communicate, and they needs leaders.
If you want to be a leader, don&amp;rsquo;t be boring. Do a great job instead.
 &amp;ldquo;Good enough&amp;rdquo; stopped being good enough a long time ago. So why not be great? — Seth Godin
 Don&amp;rsquo;t try to be a leader just because you can or for selfish reasons; wait for your right cause.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Way of the Superior Man</title>
      <link>https://gaston.life/books/the-way-of-the-superior-man/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaston.life/books/the-way-of-the-superior-man/</guid>
      <description>Stop waiting for the good stuff to come, look for it yourself. Spend at least 1 hour a day doing whatever you&amp;rsquo;re currently waiting to do.
Listen to others and then make a decision based on your new perspective. It&amp;rsquo;s your responsibility to make your own decision. Never betray yourself and your values to please anyone.
Don&amp;rsquo;t seek fulfillment, neither through work nor women, you&amp;rsquo;re already full.
Your Edge  A superior man is free in feeling and action, even amidst great pain and hurt.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some Thoughts About Relationships</title>
      <link>https://gaston.life/books/some-thoughts-about-relationships/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaston.life/books/some-thoughts-about-relationships/</guid>
      <description>All relationships are different. These guidelines should serve as ideas on which to build your own guidelines. Figure out what makes sense to you, and commit on a daily basis.
Develop the habit of questioning the pre-established notions about relationships. Never play a predetermined role.
Stress test your relationship by traveling together. The randomness and uncertainty of traveling brings up the best and worst of everyone.
Be Rational Believe in cause and effect, continuous improvement, and looking for solutions to problems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lying</title>
      <link>https://gaston.life/books/lying/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaston.life/books/lying/</guid>
      <description>Lies  To lie is to intentionally mislead others when they expect honest communication. — Sam Harris
 Don&amp;rsquo;t lie, even if you think a white lie is better than being honest. You don&amp;rsquo;t know when it might turn itself around and generate more harm than good.
Don&amp;rsquo;t intentionally communicate something you don&amp;rsquo;t believe. Others might act on that falsehood, generating all kinds of problems that you may not be able to predict.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
