<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>athletics on </title>
    <link>https://gaston.life/tags/athletics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in athletics on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://gaston.life/tags/athletics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Convict Conditioning</title>
      <link>https://gaston.life/books/convict-conditioning/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaston.life/books/convict-conditioning/</guid>
      <description>Note: These notes doesn&amp;rsquo;t include the actual calisthenics program explained in the book.
 Calisthenics (&amp;hellip;) it comes from the ancient Greek kallos meaning &amp;ldquo;beauty&amp;rdquo;, and sthénos, which means &amp;ldquo;strength&amp;rdquo;. — Paul Wade
 Calisthenics is a strength training system.
These are the main benefits of doing calisthenics:
 It requires very little equipment because they are exercises using your own bodyweight. It&amp;rsquo;s also free. It develops functional athletic abilities because you learn to work and move your body.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Burn the Fat, Feed the Muscle</title>
      <link>https://gaston.life/books/burn-the-fat-feed-the-muscle/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaston.life/books/burn-the-fat-feed-the-muscle/</guid>
      <description>To improve your body (getting leaner and healthier) you need to work on different areas. Achieving a very lean body is the result of a lifestyle change.
There areas you need to work on are the following:
 Mental training Nutrition Weight training Cardio training  To obtain permanent results you need to adopt new, healthier habits that you can maintain for the rest of your life. These habits include the way you think, the way you eat, and the way you move.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Food Rules, An Eater&#39;s Manual</title>
      <link>https://gaston.life/books/food-rules/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaston.life/books/food-rules/</guid>
      <description>I learned that in fact science knows a lot less about nutrition than you would expect—that in fact nutrition science is, to put it charitably, a very young science. — Michael Pollan
 Two facts about nutrition and diet:
 Western diet (lots of processed food, added sugar and fat, refined grains) correlates with obesity, type 2 diabetes, cardiovascular disease, and cancer. Other diets generally don&amp;rsquo;t suffer from these chronic diseases.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sleep Smarter</title>
      <link>https://gaston.life/books/sleep-smarter/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaston.life/books/sleep-smarter/</guid>
      <description>Being awake breaks your body and sleep is the way to fix it and make it stronger.
You need sleep to have the body and health you want. You can&amp;rsquo;t be the best version of yourself if you&amp;rsquo;re tired.
See sleep as an incredible indulgence, as something you&amp;rsquo;re really looking forward to.
General Advice Avoid using sunglasses, they inhibit the natural exposure to light you need.
Learn to use coffee. Coffee has a 6 hours half-life.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
