<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>productivity on </title>
    <link>https://gaston.life/tags/productivity/</link>
    <description>Recent content in productivity on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://gaston.life/tags/productivity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Master Todoist</title>
      <link>https://gaston.life/books/master-todoist/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaston.life/books/master-todoist/</guid>
      <description>You can&amp;rsquo;t store all your ideas, tasks, and appointments in your mind. Life is just too complicated.
Develop the habit of capturing everything that comes to your mind in one place and the habit of periodically reviewing them. Only by doing so, you&amp;rsquo;ll be able let go and fully concentrate on the task at hand.
 It has been said that once upon a time, the word priority was used in the singular form, which meant you could only have one priority at a time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time Well Spent</title>
      <link>https://gaston.life/books/time-well-spent/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaston.life/books/time-well-spent/</guid>
      <description>Time management is not about managing time. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter if you have the perfect tools or if you were able to cram up every waking minute of your day with tasks.
If you&amp;rsquo;re doing too many thing you&amp;rsquo;ll end up exhausted without enjoying life.
If you&amp;rsquo;re doing the wrong things you&amp;rsquo;ll end up where you never wanted to be.
If you&amp;rsquo;re not doing anything you&amp;rsquo;ll end up hating that “freedom” and reacting to whatever happens around you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>To-Do List Makeover</title>
      <link>https://gaston.life/books/to-do-list-makeover/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaston.life/books/to-do-list-makeover/</guid>
      <description>The key to make this system work is to accept that:
 Knowing how to identify what&amp;rsquo;s important is crucial. These are usually tasks with impending deadlines or tasks that has great impact to your goals. There are different types of tasks. Small tasks with clear completion criteria are easier to complete and builds momentum. Creating tasks thinking on how to achieve the end result are better. Tasks are not life or death activities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tyranny of the Urgent</title>
      <link>https://gaston.life/books/tyranny-of-the-urgent/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaston.life/books/tyranny-of-the-urgent/</guid>
      <description>If you feel like your days are too short, more time each day is not the solution. Parkinson&amp;rsquo;s Law seems to be a thing.
Fear, doubt and anxiety over the past arises when we look at all our unfinished tasks.
Realise the fact that urgent tasks are taking time from important tasks.
This is a problem of priorities, not time. The problem is the choice you make.
It&amp;rsquo;s not your responsibility to do something just because you can, however urgent it is.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Make it Stick</title>
      <link>https://gaston.life/books/make-it-stick/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaston.life/books/make-it-stick/</guid>
      <description>Learning: we mean acquiring knowledge and skills and having them readily available from memory so you can make sense of future problems and opportunities. — Peter Brown
 Learning is a skill. Develop it, as it&amp;rsquo;ll be your most valuable skill.
Learning is hard and it usually isn&amp;rsquo;t enjoyable. It depends more on the kind of effort spent while learning than on genetics. Be patient and determined.
In practice, there&amp;rsquo;s no limit to what we can remember.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resting into Productivity</title>
      <link>https://gaston.life/writings/resting/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaston.life/writings/resting/</guid>
      <description>We all like to learn and be good at what we do. Right?
But, have you ever found yourself trying to be productive by making the most of idle moments? Answering emails at waiting rooms, listening to audiobooks while driving, or reading books cover to cover to learn new things?
Are you convinced that to be more productive you have to work more hours and reducing your not working moments?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Todoist and Pomodoros</title>
      <link>https://gaston.life/writings/todoist/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaston.life/writings/todoist/</guid>
      <description>I will not explain what Todoist or The Pomodoro Technique are nor its benefits. There are already lots of articles and blog posts doing that. I will only say that if you haven&amp;rsquo;t used them, you should at least try them. (I understand that they might not work for you, but it might give you a hint on what might.) If you are already using them, then awesome!
On this article I will focus on how to use them together since Todoist doesn&amp;rsquo;t support The Pomodoro Technique out of the box.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
